NISHI SHETH

Phone: 0481 824 189 | E-Mail: nishivsheth@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/nishisheth

LinkedIn: https://au.linkedin.com/in/nishisheth

Work Eligibility: Australian Citizen

Summary

- More than 3 years of experience in developing web applications and providing customer support
- More than 1 year of experience working as technical support engineer duties
- Capable of quickly learning and delivering solutions as an individual and as part of a team.
- Hand on experience in working with agile software lifecycle methodologies.
- Responsibilities include bug fixing, adding feature requests, enhancements and new development.

Technical Skills

UI Web Technologies: HTML, HTML 5, JavaScript, NodeJS, CSS

Framework: Microsoft .Net, C#, ASP.Net

IDE and tools: Notepad++, Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio, Microsoft Office suite

Databases: Microsoft SQL Server (T-SQL), MySQL

Public cloud: Amazon Web Services (EC2, Lightsail, S3, Route 53, ELB etc.)

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux and MacOS

Methodologies: Agile, analysis work, design work, estimation, business interaction

Education

Full Stack Web Developer, Nano Degree June 2019 - Sep 2019

Udacity

Masters in Information Technology Aug 2012 - Jun 2014

Sardar Patel University, India

Bachelor in Business Administration May 2007 - Jun 2011

Sardar Patel University, India

Major: Information System Management

Experience

Web Developer Emega Online, Glendenning, NSW

Sep 2019 - Nov 2021

- Developed front-end of inventory system using Node JS, HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Designed independent components to support different functions on internal warehouse operations.
- Created node modules to perform CRUD operation using REST API to support front-end application for more than 1000 items.
- **Developed database stored procedures** to perform ETL on raw data.
- Worked with off shore team on project planning, execution and reviewing work
- Worked with product manager to understand requirements and solve bugs in the system.
- Provided support for technical customer queries and regular releases in to production.

Software Developer Madhuvan Securities Pvt. Ltd, India

Jul 2014 - Sep 2016

- Designed and developed investment portfolio tracker applications to serve more than 3000 customers on daily basis using ReactJS, ASP .NET, SQL Server and C#.
- Developed and deployed **RESTful APIs** to support multiple features of web application.
- Provided support for developed applications to resolve customer issues and production incidents.
- Designed web pages using Java script/ HTML, ReactJS, JQuery and CSS3
- Thorough understanding of CSS principles with a clear ideology for managing maintainable, scalable and cross-browser code.
- Coordinated with the Product Owners to get the details of requirements and translate them in to working code.
- Created **ETL** processing system using Microsoft **SSIS** and T-SQL stored procedures.
- Created database objects such as stored procedures, triggers, and functions using T-SQL to generate different investment tracking reports using Microsoft SSRS.
- Performed **unit testing**, **integration testing** along with **automated test** cases using selenium, and other tools such as Sauce Labs.